<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>England's calamities discover'd with the proper remedy to restore her ancient grandeur and policy / humbly presented by James Whiston.</title>
            <author>Whiston, James, 1637?-1707.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1696</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 70 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 21 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A65663</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing W1686</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R15115</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12255690</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12255690</idno>
            <idno type="VID">57429</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A65663)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 57429)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 161:3)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>England's calamities discover'd with the proper remedy to restore her ancient grandeur and policy / humbly presented by James Whiston.</title>
                  <author>Whiston, James, 1637?-1707.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>40 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for the author, and are to be sold by Joseph Fox ... R. Clavel ... and T. Minton ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1696.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Columbia University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Sale of public office --  England.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1642-1649.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  William and Mary, 1689-1702.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-03</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:57429:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:57429:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>England<hi>'s Calamities Diſcover'd:</hi> WITH THE Proper Remedy To Reſtore Her Ancient <hi>Grandeur</hi> and <hi>Policy.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Humbly Preſented By James Whiſton.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>What</hi> Captain <hi>and</hi> Mariners, <hi>when they find the</hi> Ship <hi>driven by a violent</hi> Hurricane <hi>among the</hi> Rocks, <hi>full of</hi> Leaks, <hi>and much</hi> Diſabled, <hi>will be ſo</hi> Obſtinately <hi>Inſenſible of the Conſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quence of ſuch Fatal Circumſtances, as not to <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſe their</hi> Own, <hi>and Embrace the good Endeavours of</hi> Others, <hi>for their Preſerva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion? The</hi> only <hi>Means of Hope left, whereby</hi> Themſelves <hi>and</hi> Ship <hi>may at laſt be Conducted into a ſafe</hi> Harbour.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed for the Author, and are to be ſold by <hi>Joſeph Fox</hi> in <hi>Weſtminſter-Hall, R. Clavel</hi> at the Peacock in <hi>Fleetſtreet,</hi> and <hi>T. Minton,</hi> at the Anchor under the <hi>Royal Exchange.</hi> 1696.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:57429:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:57429:2"/>
            <head>England<hi>'s Calamities Diſcovered:</hi> WITH THE Proper Remedy TO RESTORE <hi>Her Antient Grandeur and Policy.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>IT is not unknown to the World what a diffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cult Task is here undertaken; and we may, without pretence to the Gift of Prophecy, fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tell how many, and what ſort of Enemies an honeſt Man is to grapple with, in defence of this one Uſeful, and Unqueſtion'd <hi>Principle,</hi> viz.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>That every happy Government muſt be Supported by juſt Means; and that State which has been ſo far Miſtaken in it's Politicks, as to practice a contrary Method, has always drawn upon it ſelf its own Ruin and Deſtruction.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:57429:3"/>
            <p> AND upon this Obſervation it has been Granted in all Ages, That a Throne that would Flouriſh, muſt be eſtabliſhed in <hi>Righteouſneſs:</hi> but we never heard of any that has been long ſupported by <hi>Iniquity:</hi> For Iniquity its ſelf muſt be obliged to Juſtice; or at leaſt, to thoſe that fill the Seats of Juſtice, for it's Support and Main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenance. And where the execution of <hi>this</hi> fails, all Combinations or Societies of Men, however formed, naturally fall into Diſorder and Diſſolution.</p>
            <p>NOW ſince neither the Apprehenſion of Enemies, the Power or Malice of Men, who have by any means Wriggled themſelves into the pretended Service of the Government, nor the Difficulty of the Undertaking, which is to beget in Mankind a belief of ſuch Truths and Qualities as this corrupt Age has hardly Vertue enough to put in Practice, ought to deter a true <hi>Engliſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man</hi> from laying open, as occaſion ſerves, thoſe Miſchiefs and Miſcarriages, which, if not timely prevented, will Overwhelm us: I thought it an indiſpenſible Duty, to give theſe freſh Teſtimonies of Love to my Country, and Allegiance to King <hi>WILLIAM,</hi> by rendring both Inexcuſable, when the Conſequential Miſeries of the Abuſes, and Corruptions here complain'd of, ſhall have reduced us to a too late Repentance.</p>
            <p>A chief Means for the Preſervation of a State or Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment in good Order is, That particular Care be taken not to Stifle and Diſcountenance, but Admit and Che<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh the juſt Impeachments, and reaſonable Accuſations (which are the unqueſtionable Right of the Subject) againſt thoſe, who being biaſs'd by Ambition, Avarice or Pride, ſhall either contrary to Law, or by <hi>Eluſion</hi> and corrupt practice of the Law, ſeek to Invade and deſtroy their Liberties Properties, and Native Rights.</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:57429:3"/>
            <p> THE want of a due, and impartial Adminiſtration of Juſtice in <hi>this</hi> Particular, has been the grand Cauſe of all the Cruelty, Oppreſſion and Extortion that have ſo often interrupted the publick Peace, and now hang over the Nation as a ſevere Judgment.</p>
            <p>I wou'd not be miſunderſtood, as if I intended to fill the KIngdom with perpetual Clamours and Informations, and deſign'd to open a wide door of Acceſs for every little <hi>Whiffler</hi> to allarm the Magiſtrates Quiet with petty vexatious Complaints, and malicious Suggeſtions. I abhor that ſort of Cattle, and the indulging them, as much as any Man alive. But it is Unjuſt in it ſelf, and of fatal Conſequence to a Government, to Reproach and Stigmatize every honeſt Man with the ſcandal of Common Informer, who out of a true ſenſe of his Duty, and an unbiaſs'd Zeal for his King and Country, ſhall endeavour to detect the wicked Practices of ſuch, who by corruptly abuſing the honourable Imployments they are intruſted with, directly ſtrike at the Life and Happineſs of both. I ſay ſuch Informations as theſe ought to be aſſiſted with the Encouragement of the Magiſtrate, eſpecially if the Complaints are grounded upon reaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able Evidence, or even upon probable Suſpicion: Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept they will tell us they have made ſuch good Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion afore-hand, to ſupply the Executive part of the Government with honeſt and able Officers, that it is morally impoſſible for a Man in Office, to act againſt his Conſcience, or betray his Truſt for Money. This wou'd be good News indeed, and at once diſcharge the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of their Complaints and Fears, and eaſe his Majeſty of the greateſt part of his Care and Danger.</p>
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:57429:4"/>
            <p> BUT, alas! our preſent Circumſtances afford us ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parent Reaſons to believe the contrary; and the Evils and Diſaſters that have continually attended us, take away the very pretence, or umbrage of any Excuſe whatever. This is too viſible to be denied, when the diſpoſal of Truſt and Power, in too many places in the Government, is ſet to Sale to the higheſt <hi>Bidder;</hi> or what is as bad, beſtow'd upon <hi>Favouries,</hi> or private <hi>Minions,</hi> tho' never ſo Unqualified; many Offices being only to be obtain'd by Money: Which infamous Practice intails theſe two fatal Calamities upon the Nation, the very Source and Spring of unavoidable Miſchief and Diſor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der. For by this means, many Perſons, utterly incapa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble of diſcharging the Duty of the Employments they hold, by virtue of a ſtrong <hi>Purſe,</hi> tho' never ſo weak <hi>Capacity,</hi> are admitted into ſuch part of the Public Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſtration, where this <hi>Ignorance</hi> and <hi>Inabillity</hi> render them wholly Unſerviceable, and conſequently <hi>Truſt</hi> no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>toriouſly Miſ-managed, to the Governments irreparable Prejudice.</p>
            <p>AND tho' we'll ſuppoſe <hi>ſome</hi> Purchaſer to be fitly Qualified, and of <hi>honeſt</hi> Principles, yet by reaſon of this heavy Fine for his Admiſſion, he lies under the daily Temptation of ſtretching the Duty of his Office, in raiſing his Fees to re-advance his Purchaſe-Money. By which means, too many Places, wherein the Honour of the Truſt, with a moderate Sallary, would otherwiſe be an ample Gratification, are now become a perfect Mart of <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſury</hi> and <hi>Intereſt;</hi> with this farther Inconvenience, That all the <hi>Sub-miniſters</hi> and inferiour Officers, lying under their Maſters Circumſtances, being wholly ſway'd by Lucre and Profit are likewiſe expoſed to the very ſame Temptations in their lower <hi>Claſs</hi> of Truſt. And what is ſtill more Calamitous, Their Miſdemeanours and
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:57429:4"/>Faults muſt be but very ſlenderly Inſpected; or at beſt but mildly Puniſht, leſt otherwiſe you ſtrike at the Offenders Farm, I may ſay his <hi>Fee-Simple,</hi> his down<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>right <hi>Purchaſe</hi> and <hi>Penniworth.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>THIS is deflouring the Virgin Purity of Juſtice, checking and curbing her in the Nobleſt Exerciſes of her Dominion, and adminiſtring a plauſible Colour for defending Injuſtice, Bribery, Extortion and Oppreſſion. But to double and treble the Value, to manage them for the beſt advantage to the Seller, and put him upon the Rack of Improvement too; what is it but to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpeak the unfitteſt Men, either through want of Hone<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſty or Experience, that can be met with to manage thoſe Affairs and Places, in which Juſtice and Reaſon require the moſt Upright and Judicious Perſons?</p>
            <p>BUT that the Deformity, as well as Iniquity of ſuch an abominable Practice, may become more Odious, by being made more Viſible and Conſpicuous (tho' there are too many other Grievances in the Nation to be La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mented) for brevity ſake we ſhall make ſome particular Remarks, and commence our Reflections from the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable City of <hi>London,</hi> the grand Pattern by whoſe Meaſures ſmaller Corporations are apt to make their Precedents.</p>
            <p>UNEXPRESSIBLE are the daily Complaints and Miſchiefs, that ariſe through the Exceſſive ſtraining and advancing the exorbitant Fees of <hi>Councellors, Attorneys, Clerks, Serjeants, Goalers,</hi> and other Officers in this City, by reaſon of the too frequent, malicious, and impertinent Actions, and general Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruption among them: Occaſion'd chiefly by their being forced to <hi>buy</hi> their Places with Money, without regard
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:57429:5"/>to Merit. For never any Man came into an Office by the Mediation of his <hi>Gold,</hi> but he was compell'd to exerciſe his Authority wickedly. He that Buys muſt Sell, or he loſes by the Bargain; which makes the <hi>Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Offices</hi> to be like <hi>Briars,</hi> to which Sheep repairing for Shelter, muſt unavoidably be forced to part with ſome of their <hi>Fleece.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>NOW to conſider the Conſequences, and thoſe very pernicious ones, of ſuch <hi>Purchaſe,</hi> we'll begin with the <hi>Serjeant,</hi> who at this time pays the Sheriff near 500 <hi>l.</hi> for his Place: 'tis true, it has been at a far lower Rate, (as well as all other places) but the Prices riſe as the World degenerates, and conſequently Corruptions im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prove and increaſe.</p>
            <p>WELL, ſuppoſe here is 500 <hi>l.</hi> given for a Place for Life, which at ſeven Years purchaſe, the cuſtomary value of a Life, buys 70 <hi>l. per Annum</hi> in a dead Rent upon Land, where the Purchaſer has no more to do, than receive his <hi>Annual</hi> Revenue as the Money becomes due. But in a Place or Office purchas'd, where there is conſtant Toil, Attendance, and Buſineſs to ſupply that Office, 'tis modeſtly Computed, That a Man Ought in all Reaſon and Equity to make double as much <hi>per Annum</hi> of his Money as in a lazy Annu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ity. So that for his 500 <hi>l.</hi> a <hi>Serjeant</hi> ſeems to have a juſtifyable Pretenſion to get about 150 <hi>l.</hi> a Year; a very round Income, for a Man that in his poſt, is ſworn but a <hi>Varlet;</hi> an Income much larger than that of many an honeſt Gentleman of good Birth and Quality, with much a fairer <hi>Blazon</hi> in his Coat of Arms, than a Blood-ſucking-<hi>Serjeant.</hi> This 150 <hi>l. per Annum</hi> is 3 <hi>l.</hi> a <hi>Week,</hi> about 10 <hi>s.</hi> a <hi>Day;</hi> and how muſt the <hi>Serjeant</hi> raiſe this Money? If by taking only the now
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:57429:5"/>Cuſtomary Fees of his Office, as allow'd in Court, <hi>viz. Half a Crown</hi> for every Arreſt, and no more, of which his <hi>Yeoman,</hi> who gives above 200 <hi>l.</hi> for his Place, goes one Thirds ſnack with him; by conſequence he muſt Arreſt ſix Men every Day one with another all the Year round, to raiſe the Profits of his Purchaſe-Money, <hi>viz.</hi> 10 <hi>s. per Diem</hi> for his own ſhare.</p>
            <p>BUT, ſuppoſing this <hi>Serjeant</hi> inſtead of ſix Arreſts in one Day, does not make above ſix, and half ſix more in the whole Week, and a good Week's work too; How muſt the Money riſe then? Inſtead of Half-Crowns from the poor <hi>Priſoners,</hi> here muſt be Half-Pounds, and whole Pounds too, extorted for <hi>Civility</hi>-Money, as they call it, and ſeveral other unreaſonable Pretences and Demands, to make up the Sum.</p>
            <p>AND What, I pray, are the Conſequences of theſe Pounds ſo extorted? Only this: The poor <hi>Debtor</hi> is ſo much the <hi>Leſs</hi> enabled to ſatisfy his Creditors juſt Debt it ſelf; and all by ſuch unwarrantable Extortions, from the <hi>Serjeant</hi> firſt, and then from the <hi>Goaler</hi> afterwards, not only to the intire Defrauding the Creditor, but ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny times to the utter Ruin of the poor Priſoner, that periſhes in <hi>Goal</hi> under no other Load.</p>
            <p>Who then (the Caſe thus fairly ſtated) lays all this Oppreſſion upon a poor Debtor? The <hi>Serjeant</hi> and <hi>Goalers?</hi> No; But Mr. <hi>Sheriff,</hi> that ſells them their Places: For they, good Men, do no more than raiſe the Effects and Perquiſits, anſerable to their own fair <hi>Purchaſe</hi>-Penny.</p>
            <pb n="10" facs="tcp:57429:6"/>
            <p> IF the common Right of <hi>Meum</hi> and <hi>Tuum</hi> thus ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifeſtly ſuffers, by the Creditors want of his Legal Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfaction, occaſioned by theſe Arreſt or Impriſonment Extortions; Do the <hi>Serjeant</hi> and <hi>Goaler</hi> obſtruct that Right? Not in the leaſt. Mr. <hi>Sheriff</hi> has borrowed a round Sum of Money of the <hi>Serjeant</hi> and <hi>Yeoman</hi> for their Admiſſion, and their great <hi>City Lords</hi> and <hi>Maſters</hi> poſſibly ſix times as much of the <hi>Goalers;</hi> and therefore their Tallies and Loans muſt be ſatisfied firſt.</p>
            <p>IF a poor Priſoner, through ſuch extorted Sums, is reduced to Starving in <hi>Goal,</hi> are his <hi>Catch-poles</hi> and <hi>Turn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keys</hi> in Fault? No, not they. For their <hi>Head Office Jobbers,</hi> their great <hi>Sales-maſters</hi> have Squeez'd firſt, and 'tis their turn to Squeeze next. In fine, the Face of the Poor is <hi>Ground,</hi> but the <hi>Serjeants, Jailors, Attorneys,</hi> &amp;c. only turn the <hi>Grind-ſtone,</hi> the <hi>Grind-ſtone</hi> it ſelf is the Magiſtrate.</p>
            <p>THE <hi>Keepers Place</hi> of <hi>Newgate</hi> was lately Sold for 3500 <hi>l.</hi> Now upon ſuch a prodigious Sum paid only for the <hi>Head Tyrants</hi> Juriſdiction of thoſe Stone Walls, and Iron Grates; conſidering likewiſe the numerous <hi>Turn-keys, Sutlers,</hi> and all his <hi>Sub-Janizaries,</hi> to be all Fed and Fatten'd alſo from the Fees of their lower Poſts, what Annual Income muſt that one <hi>Goal</hi> raiſe, and how raiſe, to anſwer ſuch a Sawcy Purchaſe? Why truly thus:</p>
            <p>FIRST, <hi>For the Criminal Priſoners:</hi>
            </p>
            <p>IF a <hi>Thief,</hi> or <hi>Houſe-breaker</hi> would get unloaded of ſo many pounds of Iron, or purchaſe a Sleeping-hole, a little free from Vermine, or with wholſome Air enough to keep his Lungs from being choak'd up; he
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:57429:6"/>muſt raiſe thoſe extravagant Sums to pay for it, as can no ways be furniſht but from Theft and Vice, ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plyed by his <hi>Jades</hi> or <hi>Brother-Rogues</hi> abroad, who muſt <hi>Rob</hi> or <hi>Whore,</hi> to ſupport him even with the common Neceſſaries of Life. Nay, inſtead of employing their time in amendment of Life, and a Religious preparati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on for their Tryal, they are forced to Drink, Riot, and Game, to curry Favour with the Goaler, and ſupport his Luxury.</p>
            <p>THUS a <hi>Goal</hi> which ſhould be a Check to Roguery and Wickedneſs, in a high meaſure, by it's Extortion and Oppreſſion, Encourages it.</p>
            <p>AND next, for the poor <hi>Debtor</hi> committed thither, (for 'tis the <hi>County-Goal</hi>) he receives much the like ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vere Treatment and Hardſhips: For Extortion and Oppreſſion, like the Grave, make no Diſtinction.</p>
            <p>NOW let us enquire by what Right the Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrates ſell that Keepers place, together with thoſe of <hi>Ludgate</hi> and the <hi>Compters.</hi> 'Tis well known that thoſe Places, as well as all others, were formerly given <hi>Gratis.</hi> Now, if they had then any Inherent power of Selling them, 'tis preſumed that the <hi>then</hi> Magiſtrates were not ſo extravagantly Generous to part with ſuch a conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable Feather in the <hi>City Cap</hi> for nothing, provided they had a Title to Sell. Then, as they took nothing, ſo we may reaſonably preſume they could Rightfully Demand nothing for them.</p>
            <p>BY what pretenſion then does the <hi>Chair</hi> Demand it now? We know of no Donation or Conceſſion granted by Law to Entitle them to ſuch a Sale. And without ſuch a Donation, 'tis all but Encroachment, Iniquity,
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:57429:7"/>Injuſtice and Uſurpation, where there was no Original or Fundamental Claim to Warrant and Introduce their Pretenſions: Nay it is expreſly againſt the Commands of GOD, and the Laws of the Land, as is here made Appear.</p>
            <p>NOW for the Effects of this Corruption, How often have the ſuffering Priſoners Remonſtrated againſt all this Cruelty, and petition'd the Magiſtracy for a Redreſs of their Grievances, and a Retrenchment of the Exorbitant Demands of a <hi>Goal?</hi> But all their Prayers have either never been heard, or never minded. For the Magiſtracy is Deaf to ſuch a Work of Reformation, by reaſon his own Intereſt is concerned in the matter; and therefore the Abuſes and Oppreſſions of the <hi>Goaler</hi> (who not only repays himſelf, but acquires oft-times a great Eſtate to boot) are ſtill Connived at.</p>
            <p>HAVING been thus more particular in the <hi>Goalers</hi> and <hi>Serjeants</hi> Caſe, we ſhall leave the Reader himſelf to judge, what no leſs hard Meaſures we daily Groan under, without Relief, from <hi>Councellors, Attorneys,</hi> and <hi>Clerks,</hi> &amp;c. in their Sphere of Law, when about 1500 <hi>l.</hi> is paid for a <hi>City-Council,</hi> or <hi>Attorneys</hi> place (and divers other Officers) which by the ſame fore-mentioned Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion of Annual Advantage, muſt raiſe near 500 <hi>l. per Annum</hi> to ballance the exceſſive Price they pay for them. And tho' they live at very extravagant Rates, yet if they enjoy their Places any conſiderable time, they leave great Eſtates behind them.</p>
            <p>'TIS by this means that purchas'd Cruelty grows bold, and plumes it ſelf in its Extortion, being not on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Countenanced, but Juſtifyed by the Magiſtrate, who raiſes the Value of an unlawful Sale, becauſe he finds
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:57429:7"/>a numerous ſort of People thriving and doing <hi>well,</hi> by living and doing <hi>ill.</hi> 'Tis Example that corrupts us all: For how commonly do the Under-<hi>Officers, Goalers,</hi> &amp;c. excuſe their Barbarity, and unreaſonable Exactions, in alledging that they have no other way to make up the intereſt of their Purchaſe-Money? So that they are hereby forced to lay the whole deſign of their Advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage upon the Calamities of the Miſerable; which in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>humanity is too frequently conniv'd at by the Magiſtrate, ſuffering Juſtice to be over-ruled by the perſwaſion of many Golden Temptations. A Degenerate and Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worthy Practice! quite contrary to the Office of a Good Magiſtrate, whoſe Duty and Glory conſiſts in curbing the growth of Oppreſſion, retrenching Exorbitances, and in Searing away the <hi>proud Fleſh</hi> of Rapine and Violence, and not in Selling Impunity to the Evil-Doer.</p>
            <p>'TIS this alone that Steels and <hi>Caſe-hardens</hi> a <hi>Goaler's</hi> Conſcience againſt all Pity and Remorſe, giving him the Confidence to demand Extortionary Fees and rackt-Chamber-Rent from his Priſoners, or elſe crowding them into <hi>Holes, Dungeons,</hi> and <hi>Common-ſides,</hi> (deſignedly made more Naſty, to Terrify the Priſoner, who for preſerva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of his Life is thereby forced to part with his Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney; or) there to be Devoured by Famine and Diſeaſes.</p>
            <p>THIS makes him let his <hi>Tap-Houſes</hi> at ſuch prodi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gious Rates, that where poor People ought to have the Beſt and Cheapeſt, they have the worſt in Quality, and Smalleſt in Quantity, at exceſſive Prices: Alſo Farming his Beds to meer <hi>Harpies,</hi> and his great Key to ſuch pieces of Imperious Cruelty, as are the worſt of Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kind, to the eternal Reproach of the <hi>City</hi>'s Honour, and Scandal of the <hi>Chriſtian</hi> Religion, while the bloated <hi>Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tron</hi> himſelf, all the while, maintains his Family in
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:57429:8"/>Pride, and an Imperious Wife, or perhaps Impudent <hi>Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtriſs,</hi> in Exceſs and Luxury, with what he has Uncon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcionably drained from the Ruin of the Unfortunate. But ſee, I pray, whither will not theſe Lewd and Infa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mous Precedents at laſt lead us, when even the common Hang-man, encourag'd no doubt by theſe Examples, will ſcarcely give a <hi>Malefactor</hi> a caſt of his Office without a Bribe, very Formally, forſooth, demanding his Fees, and <hi>Higgling</hi> too, as nicely with him, as if he was going to do him ſome mighty Favour?</p>
            <p>I will appeal now to the Tribunal of Juſtice it ſelf, by what Law or what Authority, not claiming under the bad Title of illegal Cuſtom, any <hi>Sheriff,</hi> who is the immediate <hi>Goaler</hi> himſelf, and ought (as we ſhall here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after prove by reciting the Law) to receive the Priſoner <hi>Gratis</hi> into Cuſtody, can ſo Unjuſtly preſume to Sell the Deputation of any man's Liberty and Life to the controul of Sordid and Imperious Avarice? I would fain know by what Surmiſe of Common Senſe (and it wou'd be very hard, if Common Law and Common Senſe ſhould not agree) a Keeper of a Priſon can De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand a Recompence or Fee of a Priſoner for detaining him in Priſon.</p>
            <p>THERE is an Admiſſion-Fee, he Cries; As if any perſon can deſerve a Reward for opening the Door of Miſery and Deſtruction to his Neighbour and common Friend: For being ſo Civil as to admit him into the horrid Grave and Abyſs of Impriſonment.</p>
            <p>THERE is a Diſmiſſion-Fee too: As if it were reaſonable to Demand Money for letting him go, whom the Law has ſet free.</p>
            <pb n="15" facs="tcp:57429:8"/>
            <p> ABUNDANCE of ſuch Abſurdities muſt of ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſity follow; to which no Law of GOD or Man, nor no Senſe or Reaſon, can afford the leaſt ſhadow or pretext of Countenance, (nay they all forbid and condemn it) beſides that unanſwerable one before-mentioned, <hi>viz. That the Officers buy their Places, and therefore 'tis Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable in them they ſhould make the beſt of 'em.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>BUT let that be once Remedied, and the whole <hi>Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bel</hi> Superſtructure, erected upon ſo abominable a Found<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ation, will ſoon tumble down, to the unſpeakable Joy of all good Men, the infinite Honour of the City-Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſtrates, the comfortable Relief of the Poor, and to the long deſir'd Triumph and Reſtoration of baniſht Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice and Charity.</p>
            <p>NOW for a due Redreſs of all thoſe crying Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chiefs, chiefs, what could be more eaſily Reformed?</p>
            <p>FOR <hi>Inſtance,</hi> If the <hi>Council, Attorney, Clerk, Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeant, Goaler,</hi> &amp;c. had their places <hi>Gratis,</hi> the very Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trenchments of their exorbitant Fees, would be a Favour rather than Grievance; for whilſt the one keeps his Hundreds in his Pockets, and the other his Thouſands, he is neither under the Temptation, nor want of Extor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. This <hi>eſtabliſht</hi> Fee would not only be enough for his Maintenance, but be infinitely more to his Eaſe and Satisfaction. For in this caſe he would lye under no Care, or Neceſſity to fetch up the large Sums given for his Place, which till Recover'd, are reckon'd as ſo much Bread taken out of his Childrens Mouths.</p>
            <p>BESIDES, a moderate Perquiſite in an Office that comes free from a kind Patron's Gift, is gratefully re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived, whilſt on the contrary, there's no Thanks owing
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:57429:9"/>for a Purchaſe, tho' with never ſo large Profits. But above all, every Man would be then naturally carefull of a Legal Diſcharge of his Truſt, becauſe he holds by the Tenure of a <hi>Quam diu ſe bene geſſerit,</hi> viz. As long as he does Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſtly demean himſelf: and lies liable to be turned out for Miſdemeanours, when neither the Patron or Lord he holds from, would uphold him in In-juſtice, nor in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed could he himſelf Reaſonably Complain of being puniſht for it</p>
            <p>AND <hi>Laſtly,</hi> What could the <hi>City</hi> ſpeak more Mag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nificent in <hi>Hiſtory,</hi> than to beſtow her Places upon good Men, ſome of her own Members, unfortu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nately fallen to Decay, who would Naturally be Content with the Lawful and Modeſt Gains of their Employments? On the Contrary, what more Diſhonourable than to ſell her poor Citizens to be <hi>Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laniated</hi> and <hi>Macerated</hi> by the hand of Injuſtice; and for Money to make <hi>Slaughter-Houſes</hi> and <hi>Shambles</hi> of her Houſes of Reſtraint, which were built at the <hi>City</hi>'s Charge? For a City ſo fairly deckt with the Jewels of Freedom and Priviledge, to Sell the laſt Remains of Priſoner's Comfort? For in Selling a <hi>Goalers</hi> place, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> it Sells the Liberty, the Eſtate, the Perſon, nay the very Life of the Priſoner under his Juriſdiction: Seeing that through the cruelty of the <hi>Priſon</hi>-keepers, ſuch great numbers of poor People have been ſtript to their naked Skin, and when all was gone, have been Suffo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cated in <hi>Holes</hi> and <hi>Dungeons,</hi> to the loſs of many of their Lives, Diſhonour of our Nation, and Scandal of the <hi>Chriſtian Religion.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>FOR is it not, think ye, a goodly Sight, to behold the Tears of the poor, congealed by a Froſt of neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lected <hi>Charity</hi> and <hi>Injuſtice</hi> into a Pearl, glittering in
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:57429:9"/>the Ears of ſuch or ſuch a Lady? To ſee the Scarlet of the Receiver's Magiſtracy dyed with the Blood of helpleſs Innocents, or the purchaſe of Extortion? And to ſee ſome that ought to be the chief puniſhers of Iniquity, drinking Healths of forgetful Plenty in Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred pound Goblets, the Price of their own Infamy.</p>
            <p>ONE conſiderable Advantage that would follow the ſo much deſir'd prevention of the Sale of Places is, That the <hi>Civil</hi> Government would not find her Offices ſo over-ſtock'd with her mortal and implacable Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies, I mean ſuch as in the <hi>Late Reigns</hi> imployed their utmoſt Power in introducing upon the Nation an <hi>Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitrary</hi> and <hi>Tyrannic</hi> Sway; and ſince this Revolution have endeavoured to obſtruct the Kingdoms true Intereſt and Welfare.</p>
            <p>IS it not an indelible Reproach to the Government to ſee ſo many of her Offices now fill'd and ſupply'd with thoſe <hi>very</hi> Men, who for ſeveral Years together, were throwing Dirt in her Face, and Ridiculing and Deriding the Conſtitution it ſelf? Neither have they yet (tho' imploy'd by the Government) given any Evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence of their change of <hi>Principles,</hi> but retain ſtill the ſame Sentiments and Inclination to ſerve their Old <hi>Maſter,</hi> (as they frequently call him) when a favoura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Opportunity preſents it's ſelf on his behalf! Is it poſſible to believe that theſe <hi>Vipers,</hi> thus every where croud themſelves into places of Truſt for any other purpoſe, but only to carry on the ſame Deſigns <hi>Clande<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtinely,</hi> which they found they had not Power enough to effect <hi>Openly?</hi> It is indeed their Maſter-piece of Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licy; and that which has done their <hi>curſed Cauſe</hi> more Service than all the <hi>Strength,</hi> and <hi>Courage</hi> of the <hi>Faction</hi> cou'd otherwiſe be ever able to accompliſh. By this
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:57429:10"/>means the King and Parliament's Endeavours have been ſo continually Diſappointed, our Publick Undertakings Embarraſs'd, our Councils Diſcover'd, and Deſigns De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feated. Thus does the Government indiſcernably re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive her Mortal Wound from the very Hand ſhe Nou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes, who under the Hypocritical Mask of Serving her Intereſt, ſtrikes her to the very Heart.</p>
            <p>AND, in Fine, 'Tis by this Door only that all Men, of whatever denomination, are admitted into a Government. And this Conſideration is of greater Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portance than moſt are aware of: For as it is a cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain Inlet to unavoidable Dangers, which every pru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent <hi>State</hi> wou'd endeavour to prevent; ſo it reflects on the Wiſdom of our Government, to ſuffer the Safe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of their Perſons and the Peace and Happineſs of the Subjects to be expoſed to the Luſt and Malice of every Rich and Villainous Purchaſer.</p>
            <p>ANOTHER Inconvenience that follows the Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowance of what's here Complain'd of, is; That not only many of the King's Enemies are let into places of Truſt, but what is more deplorable, many of his real Friends are utterly lock'd out. There are ſeveral, even in this City, who have given ſuch Inſtances of their Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fection to His <hi>Majeſty,</hi> and firm Adherence and Fidelity to the Conſtitution of the preſent Government, as can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not poſſibly fall under any Doubt or Queſtion; who partly by other occaſional Accidents, are reduced almoſt to Inſupportable Neceſſities. Now is it not Inhumane, as well as Unreaſonable, to ſuffer ſo many Honeſt, Well-affected Perſons to Starve for want of Employ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment (who wou'd be glad to accept of any of the mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt Offices for a meer Lively-hood and Subſiſtance) only becauſe their Pockets are not large enough to purchaſe
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:57429:10"/>that, to which their Vertues and Abilities had before given them an unqueſtionable Right and Claim? Is not this ſufficient to diſcourage any Man from deſerving well of a Government, which makes no <hi>diſtinction</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween her <hi>Friends and Enemies,</hi> but indifferently Sells her <hi>Favours</hi> to the faireſt <hi>Chap-man?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>THE prodigious Multiplication of Officers alſo is no inconſiderable Grievance of the Publick, and the na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tural reſult of corrupt Practice of Selling of Offices. For when the <hi>Superiour</hi> have once taſted the Sweets of this ſort of Dealing, they are eaſily induced to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve, that Buſineſs may better be diſpatch'd by more Hands, and ſo unneceſſary Officers are trump'd up, as often as they have Occaſion to give a Portion with a Daughter, or Match a Son, or want to make up a Sum, to purchaſe the remaining part perhaps of a poor Cli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ents Eſtate, after the former has been ſpent in <hi>Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cil</hi>'s Fees, and paying the extravagant and exacted Fees, and Charges of their ſeveral Courts and Offices.</p>
            <p>AND by this means all the numerous Officers be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing to and depending on the Law, who were at firſt no doubt deſigned for the Service of the Public, in the Adminiſtration of Juſtice, and the defence of the Rights and Liberties of the People, are now by this Lewd Toleration of the Buying and Selling of Places, become ſo deſperately Wicked, that they ſeem to be joyn'd in Unanimous and direct Conſpiracy to Rob and Defrand the reſt of Mankind, and Violate all the Rules of Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice and good Policy.</p>
            <p>But tho' we have been ſo Earneſt and Vehement in pleading the Cauſe of the poor oppreſſed <hi>Priſoners &amp;c.</hi> Yet let us not altogether paſs by, without ſome juſt Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flections,
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:57429:11"/>the heinous Injuſtice that is every day done to the Poor, and helpleſs People at <hi>Liberty.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>THERE is one Remark that we have made, that very well deſerves the moſt ſerious and ſolemn Conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration of the Magiſtracy, of the Honourable City of <hi>London:</hi> It is this. Before this City was ſo miſerably over-ſpread with Corruption and Covetouſneſs, it was a Cuſtom no leſs Honourable in it's Inſtitution, than ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treamly Uſeful and Chriſtian in it's end, for the Two and Fifty Companies, to have their particular Grana<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries where they us'd to ſtore up great Quantities of Sea-Coal, and Thouſands of Quarters of Corn, which was bought with the Charity of thoſe who were brought upon the Livery, the Company at the ſame time giving them a Receipt with Promiſe, that if ever they ſhou'd be reduced to Want, they ſhou'd have the value of the Money laid down in Corn and Coals <hi>Gratis;</hi> which Fund was mightily advanced by many dying Perſons Bequeſts and Legacies, and the Fines of <hi>Aldermen, Sheriffs, Livery-Men,</hi> and others (which Annually amount<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to vaſt Sums.)</p>
            <p>THIS was of infinite Advantage to the whole City both Rich and Poor: For buying theſe Commodities when Cheapeſt, and going to Market with ready Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, they were Obliged in times of Scarcity to ſell 'em out to the Poor at a very moderate Price. Which com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mendable Practice has been for ſeveral Years Diſconti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nu'd to the unſpeakable Prejudice and Diſſervice of the Poor, may of whom by neglect of ſo good a Cuſtom, are reduc'd even to Starving in Winter, and times of Scarcity, yet the ſaid Money is ſtill Exacted, as due by Law, and converted to other Uſes.</p>
            <pb n="21" facs="tcp:57429:11"/>
            <p> THE inexpreſſible Advantage <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>udable and never to be forgotten Cuſtom is further Evidenced, in the frequent ſcarcity of Corn; For, ſince the City and Suburbs have near doubly increaſed the number of In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitants; and the Corn now coming into the Hands of of a very few Factors, and ſeveral Notorious Huckſters, moſt of 'em <hi>Joſeph</hi>'s Brethren, there being in all rarely a Month's (and ſometimes not a Weeks) Store in <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don:</hi> So that upon contrary Winds, Froſts, want of Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voys, or any other true or pretended Reaſons, they un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>juſtly raiſe the Market upon the Poor, on purpoſe to improve their own Profit, altho' there be enough in the Nation; an Inconvenience the <hi>City</hi> ſeldom ſuffer'd un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der in thoſe charitable Times, when the above-men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion'd cuſtom was duly obſerv'd and practic'd.</p>
            <p>THE ſame may be affirmed in the caſe of <hi>Coals,</hi> &amp;c. And this as well as the other was an Advantage like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe to the Sellers, who were under no Apprehenſion of having their Goods lye upon their Hands, becauſe they were ſure to come to a certain, tho' not always an equal Market, which kept the Plough continually going, and the <hi>Colliers</hi> Ships Sailing, to the vaſt Improvement of Navigation, and the general Satisfaction of the Nation.</p>
            <p>AND this Contagion, like the fretting Leproſie, has ſpread it ſelf over all the petty Corporations and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panies in this <hi>City,</hi> where they dayly exact extravagant Sums of Money from the toe Subject, taking ſometimes Sixteen, Twenty, Thirty and Forty ſhillings; and often<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times much more, for the admittance of every Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, whereas by the <hi>Stat.</hi> of 22. <hi>H.</hi> 8. cap. 4<hi rend="sup">o</hi> They are to receive but 3 <hi>s.</hi> 4 <hi>d.</hi> for the Entry of a Free-man, and 2 <hi>s.</hi> 6 <hi>d.</hi> for the Entry of an Apprentice.</p>
            <pb n="22" facs="tcp:57429:12"/>
            <p> BUT <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> worſe and grievous, are the Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitrary and prodigious Fines, of 15, 20, and 30 <hi>l.</hi> more or leſs, which they ſqueeze out of their Members, for coming on the <hi>Livery,</hi> and for places of <hi>Stewards, Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtants, Maſter-Wardens,</hi> and divers other Offices, to the intollerable Oppreſſion of poor Citizens, and to their utter Ruin: Contrary to thoſe moſt Antient and Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellent Laws of <hi>De Pallagio non Concedendo,</hi> the Petition of Right, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> intended for the great Bulwarks and Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riers of the Liberties and Properties of the People of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>THIS Corruption is likewiſe crept into leſſer So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cieties, even into the <hi>Pariſhes</hi> were the <hi>Parſons, Church-Wardens, Overſeers</hi> and the reſt of thoſe <hi>Parochial</hi> Officers exerciſe the greateſt Injuſtice imaginable, in taking Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſive and Arbitrary Sums of Money for Burying in <hi>Churches</hi> and <hi>Church-Yards;</hi> and for <hi>Chriſtnings</hi> and <hi>Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riages;</hi> and alſo in Taxing and Exacting Money on pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence of Relieving the Poor, with a true deſign at the ſame time, to expend it in Luxury, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and forget the Miſeries of their afflicted Neighbours.</p>
            <p>A Kin to theſe Iniquities is that of the <hi>City</hi>'s Farm<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing out the Markets at 3600 <hi>l.</hi> a Year, whilſt the Farm<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers have made the Burden intollerable to the People by Extortion and Oppreſſion; and moſt Unconſcionably ſwell'd the Income to above 10000 <hi>l.</hi> a Year, as has late<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly been fully prov'd againſt them at the Inſtance and Pains of divers Well-affected Citizens. Thus is the Right and Intereſt of the Poor and Needy, Farm'd out to a parcel of Unmerciful <hi>Harpies,</hi> and <hi>Vultures,</hi> the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>humane Miniſters of Cruelty and Violence.</p>
            <pb n="23" facs="tcp:57429:12"/>
            <p> THE Caſe of the <hi>Orphans</hi> alſo ought not to be paſs'd over in Silence. We queſtion whether there has yet been Repentance enough Teſtify'd, ſufficient Reſtoration made, to clear them from the Guilt of ſuch horrible Injuſtice. We ſhall but juſt touch the point, becauſe it is ſo well known already. Was it not Scandalous, as well as abo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minably Sinful, and Injurious, for the <hi>City</hi> to aſſume a a Right to force the Eſtates of deceaſed Citizens into their own Hands, as Guardian to the poor <hi>Orphans</hi> and others: And when they had got about 700000 <hi>l.</hi> into their Cuſtody and Clutches, Unrighteouſly refuſed to pay the Moneys where they became Due, to the utter <hi>Ruin</hi> of great numbers of diſtreſſed Children (great part of whom have been forced to take Extravagant Courſes to maintain themſelves, having been neceſſitated to Sell their Eſtates to men of Money at very ſmall and inconſiderable Rates) They afterwards pretending to make Atonement, by procuring an Act of Parliament (as is well known) to Levy a Tax upon all the Perſonal Eſtates in <hi>London</hi> for ever? We pray GOD they may Repent and find Mercy.</p>
            <p>IT is not that we are Ignorant of the Abuſes com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted in ſeveral other Offices throughout the Kingdom, that we have principally confin'd our ſelves to repreſent the Miſ-management of ſome of thoſe in the <hi>City</hi> of <hi>London,</hi> but only to avoid the being too <hi>Voluminous:</hi> Theſe few Papers wou'd have ſwell'd into many <hi>Folio</hi>'s if particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar Notice had been taken of all the <hi>Corruptions</hi> and <hi>Miſcarriages</hi> under which the <hi>Nation</hi> Groans; and by which our <hi>Public Affairs</hi> have ſo miſerably Suffered, and been ſo treacherouſly Defeated.</p>
            <p>BESIDES, our Tenderneſs in <hi>Launching</hi> out further into theſe <hi>troubled Waters,</hi> has been directed by this
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:57429:13"/>Conſideration, that the Gentlemen in Places and Offices not here mentioned, (who have by their <hi>Siniſter</hi> Practices prejudiced the <hi>Intereſt,</hi> or obſtructed the Happineſs of the preſent <hi>Settlement</hi>) may, by <hi>contemplating</hi> the Deformity and evil Attendances of the <hi>City</hi> Exorbitant <hi>Corruptions,</hi> be timely made ſenſible of their Sin, and endeavour to make ſome Reparation for the <hi>Injuries</hi> they have done the Kingdom, as an <hi>Atonement</hi> and <hi>Expiation</hi> of their <hi>crying Guilt.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>THUS I think we have made it undeniably Appa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent from what <hi>Grounds</hi> our Calamities and Miſchiefs have ſprung, and by what <hi>Means</hi> they have continued their daily Progreſs to that fatal heighth, we now ſo juſtly complain of, and which requires all the Application of the Wiſdom and Power of the <hi>Government</hi> to Reſtrain and Remedy. 'Tis by Vertue of this <hi>Golden Key</hi> alone, or the <hi>Favours</hi> of <hi>unjuſt</hi> Partiality, that little or no Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gard has been had to <hi>Induſtry</hi> and <hi>Merit.</hi> That the <hi>Halt</hi> and <hi>Blind,</hi> and what is worſe, oftentimes the <hi>Malicious</hi> have been let into the Knowledge and Management of our <hi>Public</hi> Affairs, whilſt the <hi>Able</hi> and <hi>Honeſt,</hi> for want of that powerful <hi>Charm,</hi> are ſhamefully Excluded and Contemned.</p>
            <p>THIS Sale of Offices is a Practice ſo Infamous that it has been Condemn'd and Deteſted by the beſt Men, and beſt <hi>Governments</hi> in all Ages, as a curſed <hi>Omen</hi> fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boding the certain and <hi>inevitable Deſtruction</hi> of that State, where it has been in the leaſt Tolerated, and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nived at. 'Tis a ſhackling Juſtice her ſelf, a direct <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pation</hi> upon the Native and Inconteſtable Rights of <hi>Mankind,</hi> and giving a publick Licenſe for the exerciſe of <hi>Extortion</hi> and <hi>Bribery.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="25" facs="tcp:57429:13"/>
            <p> IF we at all valu'd our ſelves as Chriſtians (but that great Name is to much become a meer <hi>Cant</hi> or Term of Art to flatter our ſelves, and impoſe upon the Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dulous) our Holy Religion wou'd ſufficiently inform us of the Sinfulneſs, and Danger of this abominable Pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctice. What dreadful Judgements has the GOD of Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>partial Jnſtice thunder'd out againſt the Sale of <hi>Public</hi> Juſtice, or it's Dependencies? What exceſſive and aſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhing Penalties has he Threatned upon all manner of Extortion? Nay, ſo Severe are the terrible Denuntia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions of his Wrath, pour'd out upon all that ſhall dare to Suffer or Encourage it, as are able to ſtagger and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>found the Confidence of the moſt hardened Sinner, but his who lies under the Curſe of Final and Incorrigible <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nbelief.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>THE very Heathens themſelves abhorr'd the Conni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance, and Countenance of ſuch baſe and unworthy Proceedings: They thought it a Degree below the Dig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity of Humane Nature, to deſcend to the contemptible practice of taking <hi>Bribes,</hi> and ſelling Licenſes to <hi>Ini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quity.</hi> We find theſe two <hi>Maxims,</hi> like two <hi>Golden Pil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lars,</hi> ſupporting the moſt Flouriſhing and Victorious Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties in the World, which <hi>Ariſtotle</hi> has not been a little Induſtrious to maintain, <hi>viz. That the Sale of Offices is the greateſt Wrong, and Affront that can be Offer'd to a Common-Wealth. And that Money ought not to buy thoſe Places, which may, nay, ought to be the Reward of Vertue; and are the fitteſt means to Supply the Neceſſities of good Men.</hi> The Sale of Offices in the <hi>Meridian</hi> and Glory of the <hi>Athe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nian</hi> Government, (where Arts and Arms equally Flou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhed to the Delight and Satisfaction of all the World) was ſtrictly Forbidden, and continually Declaim'd againſt. The <hi>Lacedemonians,</hi> a People the moſt obſtinately Vertuous of all the other Cities of <hi>Greece,</hi> utterly exploded it, as a Pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctice
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:57429:14"/>altogether inconſiſtent with their ſtrict Morals, and deſtructive of the Fundamental Rules of their <hi>Policy:</hi> And I hardly believe there was ever a Human Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment better Founded than that of <hi>Sparta.</hi> The <hi>Roman</hi> Empire when it ſeem'd to be in it's greateſt Beauty, and moſt happy Condition, ſeverely Fin'd and Puniſht thoſe, who ſought Offices Unjuſtly, by Bribery, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And 'tis Remarkable, that She then firſt foſter'd <hi>Diſſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion,</hi> and laid Foundations for her after <hi>Ruin</hi> and <hi>Cala<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mities,</hi> when ſhe brook'd ſo patiently the <hi>Sarcaſtic</hi> Scoff of <hi>Jugurth, That all things at</hi> Rome <hi>are to be had for Money.</hi> 'Twas then that <hi>Rome</hi> became ſo Enfeebled by her daily Corruptions, that ſhe whoſe Vertues had made her <hi>Miſtriſs of the World,</hi> had not power enough left to Conquer her ſelf; nor cou'd ſhe hinder her own Streets from being the Stage, whereon ſo many diſmal Tragedies of inteſtine Diſcord were acted. Their <hi>Hiſtorians</hi> aſſign the Reaſon, <hi>viz. They made Juſtice a Pimp to Covetouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, and Vertue a Stalking-horſe to Extortion.</hi> Yet there was not any other City in the World, more Jealous of her Honour in this Point than <hi>Rome,</hi> or more careful to relieve the Poverty of her Citizens; of which, in the times of her Innocency ſhe had many. And what other Fate can <hi>London</hi> &amp;c. expect, if you Dam up the Current of her <hi>Meum</hi> and <hi>Tuum?</hi> If ſhe thus continue <hi>Selling</hi> of Juſtice, her Sun-ſhine and Splendor will ſoon be Ec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clips'd. In ſhort, unavoidable Ruin, is an inſeparable Subſequent of Antecedent Unrighteouſneſs.</p>
            <p>IT is very Obſervable what is Reported of the <hi>Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſian Cambyſes,</hi> how he Flead one of his Judges for Bri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bery. Certainly it had been a very unjuſt Puniſhment, if he had firſt <hi>Sold</hi> him his Place, much more if he had Farm'd it to him at a Rackt Rent; can we believe that this Judge's Son would have been willing to pay an ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:57429:14"/>Sum to ſit upon his Fathers <hi>Skin?</hi> Which how<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever he was forced to receive for his Cuſhion, (being preferr'd to his Father's Seat upon the <hi>Bench</hi>) in Order to Terrify him from the like Offence: which the <hi>King</hi> very honeſtly told him wou'd deſerve the fame Puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. This Inſtance is enough to convince us of the Neceſſity of a univerſal and equal Adminiſtration of Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice, ſince even the <hi>Perſians</hi> themſelves, one of the moſt Delicate and Effeminate Nations in the World, found the due Execution thereof, ſo eſſentially requiſite to the Preſervation of the <hi>public</hi> Peace, that they thought no Pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment too Severe for the Tranſgreſſion of ſo invio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lable a Law, upon which the Welfare of all government depends.</p>
            <p>IN Fine, there neither are, nor have been any Nations ſo Barbarous, nor any Conjunctions or united Bodies of Men ſo Inhumane, who, tho' they have exerciſed all manner of Violence and Oppreſſion towards their Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours, or their Enemies, have not at the ſame time eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſh'd and required an exact Obſervation of Juſtice among themſelves, as Fundamentally neceſſary for the maintain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the true Intereſt of their own Community.</p>
            <p>BUT our Antient <hi>Engliſh</hi> Law-makers ſeem to have a deeper Apprehenſion of the Neceſſity of this. Truth than any others; and by thoſe Noble and never be forgotten Laws they have left us, one wou'd think they had a <hi>Prophetic</hi> Reſpect to the Degeneracy of the preſent times; particularly in Relation to the Grievances, againſt which this Diſcourſe is deſign'd, as abundantly appears from the <hi>Inſtances</hi> and <hi>Citations</hi> immediately annex'd.</p>
            <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="act">
               <body>
                  <pb n="28" facs="tcp:57429:15"/>
                  <head>This Act was made <hi>Anno 5, 6. Edw.</hi> VI. Cap. <hi>16.</hi> Againſt the Sale of Offices.</head>
                  <p>THe Penalty for Buying or Selling of ſome ſort of Offices for the avoiding of Corruption which may hereafter happen to be in the Officer and Miniſters in thoſe Courts, Places or Rooms, wherein there is requiſite to be had the true Adminiſtration of Juſtice, or Services of Truſt: And to the intent that Perſons Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thy and Meet be advanced to the Place where Juſtice is to be Miniſtred, or any Service of Truſt executed, should hereafter be preferred to the ſame, and not other.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Be it therefore Enacted by the King our Soveraign Lord, the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons in this preſent Parliament Aſſembled, and by the Authority of the ſame,</hi> That if any Perſon or Perſons at any time hereafter, Bargain or Sell any Office or Offices, or Deputation of any Office or Offices, or any Part or Parcel of any of them, or receive, have, or take any Money or Fee, Reward, or any other Profit, directly or indirectly, or take any Promiſe, Agreement, Covenant, Bond, or any Aſſurance, to receive or have any Money, Fee, Reward, or other Profit, directy or indirectly, for any Office or Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, or for the Deputation of any Office or Offices, or any part of them, or to the intent that any Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon ſhould have, exerciſe or enjoy any Office or Offices, or the Deputation of any Office or Offices,
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:57429:15"/>or any part of any of them, which Office or Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, or any part or parcel of them, ſhall in any wiſe touch or concern the Adminiſtration or Execution of Juſtice, or the Receipt, Comptrolment or Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of any of the Kings Highneſs Treaſure, Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, Rent, Revenue, Account, Aulneage, Auditor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, or Surveying of any of the Kings Majeſties Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors, Caſtles, Mannors, Lands, Tenements, Woods, or Hereditaments; or any the Kings Majeſties Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtoms, or any Adminiſtration or neceſſary Atten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dance to be had, done, or executed, in any of the Kings Majeſties Cuſtom-Houſe or Houſes, the keep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of any of the Kings Majeſties Towns, Caſtles, or Fortreſſes, being uſed, occupied or appointed for a Place of Strength or Defence, or which ſhall concern or touch any <hi>Clerkship</hi> to be occupied in any man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner of <hi>Court of Record,</hi> wherein <hi>Juſtice</hi> is to be Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſtred: That then all and every ſuch <hi>Perſon</hi> and <hi>Perſons</hi> that ſhall ſo <hi>Bargain</hi> or <hi>Sell</hi> any of the ſaid <hi>Office</hi> or <hi>Offices, Deputation</hi> or <hi>Deputations,</hi> or that ſhall take any <hi>Money, Fee, Reward,</hi> or <hi>Profit,</hi> for any of the ſaid <hi>Office</hi> or <hi>Offices, Deputation</hi> or <hi>Deputati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons</hi> of any of the ſaid <hi>Offices,</hi> or <hi>any part of any of them,</hi> or that ſhall take any <hi>Promiſe, Covenant, Bond</hi> or <hi>Aſſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance</hi> for any <hi>Money, Reward,</hi> or <hi>Profit,</hi> to be given for any of the ſaid <hi>Offices, Deputation</hi> or <hi>Deputations</hi> of any of the ſaid <hi>Office</hi> or <hi>Offices,</hi> or <hi>any part of any of them,</hi> ſhall not only loſe and forfeit all his and their
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:57429:16"/>
                     <hi>Right, Intereſt</hi> and <hi>Eſtate,</hi> which ſuch <hi>Perſon</hi> or <hi>Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons</hi> ſhall then have, of, in, or to any of the ſaid <hi>Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice or Offices, Deputation or Deputations,</hi> or <hi>any part of any of them,</hi> or of, in, or to the <hi>Gift</hi> or <hi>Nomina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion</hi> of any of the ſaid <hi>Office or Offices, Deputation or Deputations,</hi> for the which <hi>Office or Offices,</hi> or for the <hi>Deputation or Deputations</hi> of which <hi>Office or Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices, or for any part of any of them,</hi> any ſuch <hi>Perſon or Perſons</hi> ſhall ſo make any <hi>Bargain or Sale,</hi> or take or receive any <hi>Sum of Money, Fee, Reward or Profit;</hi> or any promiſe, or Covenant or Aſſurance to have or receive any Fee, Reward, Money or Profit: But alſo that all and every ſuch Perſons, that ſhall give or pay any Sum of Money, Reward or Fee; or ſhall make any Promiſe, Agreement, Bond or Aſſurance for any of the ſaid <hi>Offices,</hi> or for the <hi>Deputation</hi> or <hi>Deputations</hi> of any of the ſaid <hi>Office</hi> or Offices, or any part of any of them, ſhall im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mediately by and upon the ſame Fee, Money, <hi>or</hi> Reward given <hi>or</hi> paid, <hi>or</hi> upon any ſuch <hi>Promiſe, Govenant Bond or Agreement,</hi> had <hi>or</hi> made for any Fee, Sum <hi>of</hi> Money, <hi>or</hi> Reward to be paid, as is afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, be adjudged a diſabled Perſon in the Law <hi>to</hi> all intents and purpoſes, <hi>to</hi> have, occupy or enjoy the ſaid Office <hi>or</hi> Offices, Deputation or Deputati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons or any part <hi>of</hi> any <hi>of</hi> them,<note place="margin">Cook, lib. <hi>12.78.</hi>
                     </note> for the which ſuch Perſon <hi>or</hi> Perſons ſhall ſo give <hi>or</hi> pay any Sum of Money, Fee <hi>or</hi> Reward, <hi>or</hi>
                     <pb n="31" facs="tcp:57429:16"/>make <hi>any Promiſe, Covenant, Bond or other Aſſurance,</hi> to give <hi>or</hi> pay any Sum <hi>of Money, Fee or Reward.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>And be it alſo Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid,</hi> That all and every ſuch Bargains, Sales, Promiſes, Bonds, Agreements, Covenants and Aſſurances as before Specified; ſhall be void, to and againſt Him and Them, by whom any ſuch Bargain, Sale, Bond, Promiſe, Covenant and Aſſurance ſhall be had or made.</p>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="act">
               <body>
                  <head>
                     <hi>Cook.</hi> Rep. <hi>Lib.</hi> 12.78. <hi>Hill.</hi> 8. <hi>Jac.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IN this very Term the Caſe of Dr. <hi>Trevor,</hi> who was Chancellour of a Biſhop in <hi>Wales,</hi> it was reſolved that the Office of a Chancellour and Regiſter, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in the Eccleſiaſtical Courts, are within the Statute 5 <hi>Edw.</hi> 6. <hi>Cap.</hi> 16. The Words of which Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute are, <hi>Any Office, &amp;c. which ſhall in any wiſe touch or concern the Adminiſtration or Execution of Juſtice;</hi> and the Words are ſtrongly Pen'd againſt Corruption of Officers, for they are, <hi>Which ſhall in any wiſe touch or concern the Adminiſtration,
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:57429:17"/>&amp;c.</hi> And the Preamble; <hi>And for avoid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of Corruption, which may hereafter happen to be in the Officers and Miniſters of thoſe Courts, Places, and Rooms, wherein there is requiſite to be had the true Adminiſtra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Juſtice, in Service of Truſt: And to the Intent that Perſons worthy and meet to be advanced to the Places where Juſtice is to be Miniſtred, in any Service of Truſt to be Executed, ſhall be prefered to the ſame, and none other.</hi> Which Act being made for avoiding of Corruption in Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and for the Advancement of Perſons more Worthy and ſufficient for to Execute the ſaid Offices, by which Juſtice and Right ſhall be alſo advanced, ſhall be Expounded moſt benificially to ſuppreſs Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruption. And in as much as the Law allows Eccleſiaſtical Courts to proceed in Caſe of Blaſphemy, Hereſie, Schiſm, Incontinence, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And the Loyalties of Matrimonies,
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:57429:17"/>of Divorce, of the Right of Tithes, Probate of Wills, granting of Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſtrations, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And that from theſe proceedings depend not only the Salvation of Souls, but alſo the Legitimation of Iſſues, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>And that no Debt or Duty can be recovered by Executors, or Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſtrators, without Probate of Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtaments, or Letters of Adminiſtra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, and other things of great con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſequence; It is moſt reaſon that Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers which concern the Adminiſtra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion and Execution of Juſtice in theſe Points, which concern the Salvation of Souls, and the other matters a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, ſhall be within this Statute, than Officers which concern the Adminiſtration or Execution of Juſtice in Temporal matters; for this, that Coruption of Offices in the ſaid Spiritual and Eccleſiaſtical Cauſes is more dangerous than the <hi>Officers</hi> in
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:57429:18"/>Temporal Cauſes; for the Tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poral Judge commits the Party Convict to the Coaler, but the Spiritual Judge commits the Perſon Excommunicate to the Devil. Alſo thoſe Officers do not only touch and concern the Adminiſtration of Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> But alſo are Services of great Truſt, for this, that the Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cipal End of their proceedings is, <hi>Pro Salute Animarum, &amp;c.</hi> And there is no Exceptors or Proviſo in the Statute for them.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>It was reſolved that ſuch Offices were within the</hi> Purview <hi>of the ſaid Statute.</hi>
                  </p>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="laws">
               <body>
                  <head>Here follows the Duty of a Goaler to his Priſoners, with his and other Officers Fees due by Law.</head>
                  <p>BY the Common Law we find, as <hi>Bracton</hi> Lib: 3. fol. 105. <hi>Goalers are ordained to hold Priſoners, not to puniſh them.</hi> For Impriſonment by the Law is (neither ought to be) no more than a bare reſtraint of Liberty, without thoſe illegal and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>juſt Diſtinctions of cloſe and open Priſon (as is uſual.) See <hi>Stamf.</hi> Pla. Cor. fol. 70.</p>
                  <p>Therefore <hi>Cook</hi> in his 3 Inſt. 91. ſaith, <hi>That if the Goaler keep the Priſoners more ſtreightly then he ought of Right,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Britton fol. 18.</note> 
                     <hi>whereof the Priſoner dieth, this is Felony in the Goaler by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:57429:18"/>Law. And this is the Cauſe, That if a Priſoner dye in Priſon, the Coroner ought to ſit upon him.</hi> See alſo the ſaid <hi>Cook,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Flet. lib. 1. c. 26</note> Fol. 34. <hi>cap. Petty-Treaſon;</hi> how Priſoners are to be uſed, wherein is alſo an account of an Indictment of a Coaler for evil uſage of his Priſoner, <hi>fol.</hi> 35. in <hi>Trin.</hi> 7. E. 3. <hi>cor. Rege rot.</hi> 44.-That whereas one <hi>R. B.</hi> of <hi>T.</hi> was taken and detained in the Priſon of <hi>Lincoln</hi> Caſtle,<note place="margin">1 E. 3. cap. 7.</note> for a certain Debt of Statute-Merchant, in the Cuſtody of <hi>T. B.</hi> Conſtable of the Caſtle <hi>L.</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid; That the ſaid <hi>T. B.</hi> put the ſaid <hi>R.</hi> into the Common Goal a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt Thieves in a filthy Priſon, contrary to the form of the Statute <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and there detained him till he had paid him a Fine of 40 <hi>s.</hi> Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon <hi>Cook</hi> makes this Obſervation, <hi>So as hereby it appeareth, where the Law requireth that a Priſoner ſhould be kept in ſafe and ſure Cuſtody, yet that muſt be without any Pain or Torment to the Priſoner.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>So <hi>Co.</hi> 3. Inſt. 52. ſaith, <hi>If a Priſoner by Dureſs,</hi> that is, <hi>hard uſage of the Goaler, cometh to untimely Death, this is Murther in the Goaler; and in the Law implieth Malice, in reſpect of the Cruelty.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Horn,</hi> in the Mirror of Juſtice, p. 288. ſaith, <hi>That it is an Abu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of the Law, that Priſoners are put into Irons, or other Pain, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore they are Attainted.</hi> See alſo <hi>Cook.</hi> 3. Inſt. 34.35. And <hi>Horn</hi> alſo p. 34, 35. reckons the ſtarving of Priſoners by Famine, to be a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong the Crimes of Homicide in a Goaler. <hi>Vox plebis,</hi> part 1. f. 55, 56.</p>
                  <p>Which alſo <hi>Cook</hi> in his 3. Inſt. chap. 29. Tit. <hi>Felony</hi> in Goal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers by <hi>Dureſs</hi> of Impriſonment, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by Statute and by the Common Law, <hi>Fol.</hi> 91.</p>
                  <p>And next, let us ſee what the Law ſaith for the Fees due to Goalers. The Mirror of <hi>Juſtice,</hi> pag. 288. tells us, That it is an Abuſion of the Law, that Priſoners, or others for them, pay any thing for their <hi>Entries</hi> into the Goal, or for their <hi>Going out:</hi> This is the Common Law, there is no Fee due to them by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Law. See what the Statutes ſay. The Statute of <hi>Weſtin.</hi> 1. <hi>cap.</hi> 26. ſaith, <hi>That no Sheriff, or other Miniſter of the King, ſhall take Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward for doing their Offices, but what they take of the King, if they do, they ſhall Suffer double to the Party aggrieved, and be Puniſhed at the Will of the King.</hi> Under this Word, <hi>Miniſter</hi> of the <hi>King,</hi> are included, <hi>all Eſchea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, Coroners, Goalers,</hi> &amp;c. as <hi>Cook</hi> 2. Inſt. fol. 209. affirms: And agreeable is <hi>Stampf. pl. Coron.</hi> 49. Nay by the Statute of 4. <hi>E.</hi> 3. cap. 10. Goalers are to receive <hi>Thieves</hi> and <hi>Fellons,</hi> taking nothing by way of Fees for the Receipt of them. So odious is this Extortion of <hi>Goalers</hi> that very <hi>Thieves &amp; Felons</hi> are exempt from <hi>payment of Fees.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <pb n="36" facs="tcp:57429:19"/>
                  <p> And we find in our Law-Books, That no Fees are due to any Officer, Goaler, or Miniſter of Juſtice, but only thoſe which are gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven by Act of Parliament, for if a Goaler will preſcribe for any Fees, the Preſcription is void, becauſe againſt this Act of Parliament, made 3 <hi>E.</hi> 1. being an Act made within time of Memory, and takes away all manner of pretended Fees before; and we are ſure none can be raiſed by colour of Preſcription ſince: And therefore we find by the Books of 8. <hi>E.</hi> 4. fol. 18. <hi>That a Marſhal or Goaler cannot detain any Priſoner after his diſcharge from the Court, but only for the Fees of the Court,</hi> (the Court being not barred by this Statute of <hi>Weſtm.</hi> 1. aforementioned) <hi>and if he do, he may be Indicted for Extor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion.</hi> And agreeable to this is the Book of 21 F. 7. Fol. 16. where amongſt other things it's held for Law, <hi>That if a Goaler or Guardian of a Priſon, takes his Priſoner's proper Garment, Cloak, or Money from him, it is a Treſpaſs, and the Goaler ſhall be anſwerable for it:</hi> So that we may undeniably conclude, That there is no Fee at all due to any <hi>Goaler</hi> or <hi>Guardian</hi> of a Priſon from the Priſoner, but what is due unto him by ſpecial Act of Parliament. And if a Goaler or Guardian of a Priſon, ſhall take any thing as a Fee of his Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoner, he may and ought to be <hi>Indicted</hi> of <hi>Extortion,</hi> and upon Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viction to be removed from his Office; and if his Priſoner, by <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtraint, Menace,</hi> or <hi>Dureſs,</hi> be enforced to give him Money, he may recover that Money againſt the Goaler again, in an Action of the Caſe at Common Law.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Stat. 23. <hi>H.</hi> 6. Chap. 10.</note> The King conſidering the great Perjury, Extortion, and Oppreſſion, which be and have been in this Realm, by his Sheriffs, Under-Sheriffs, and their Clerks,<note place="margin">Stat. 4. <hi>H.</hi> 4.5.</note> Bailiffs, and Keepers of Priſons, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> hath Ordained by Authority aforeſaid, in eſchewing all ſuch Extortion,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Raſt.</hi> Predict. fol. 318.</note> Perjury, and Oppreſſion, That no Sheriff ſhall let to Farm in any manner his Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, nor any of his Bayliwicks Nor that any of the ſaid Officers and Miniſters,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Cook</hi> Predict. 365.</note> by occaſion, or under colour of their Office,<note place="margin">21 <hi>H.</hi> 7. fol. 16.</note> ſhall take any other thing by them, nor by any other perſon to their uſe, profit, or avail, of any perſon by them or any of them to be Arreſted or Attached, for the omitting of any Arreſt or Attachment to be made by their Body, or of any perſon by them, or any of them, (by force or colour of their Office Arreſted or Attached, for Fine, Fee, Suit of Priſon, Main-prize, letting to Bail, or ſhewing any Eaſe or
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:57429:19"/>Favour, (to any ſuch Perſon Arreſted or to be Attached) for their Reward or Profit; but ſuch as follow, That is to ſay, For the Sheriff 20 <hi>d.</hi> The Officer which maketh the Arreſt or Attachment 4 <hi>d.</hi> And the Goaler of the Priſon, if he be com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to Ward, 4 <hi>d.</hi>—And that all Sheriffs,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Raſt,</hi> predict. fol. 371</note> Bailiffs, Goalers, or any other Officer or Miniſters, which do con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to this Ordinance in any point of the ſame, ſhall loſe to the Party in this behalf indammaged or grieved,<note place="margin">Stat. 21 Ed. 3.</note> his treble Damages, and ſhall forfeit the Sum of 40 <hi>l.</hi> for every ſuch Offence, the one Moiety to the King, the other to the Proſecutor, to be recovered at Common Law, in either of the Courts of <hi>King</hi>'s-<hi>Bench,</hi> or <hi>Common-Pleas</hi> at <hi>Weſtminſter.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>This is a perfect Account of the Goalers Fees in all Caſes, where Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons are laid in Priſon upon Civil Matters and Cauſes, which Fee of 4 <hi>d.</hi> is more then any other Statute or Law allows them to take from their Priſoners: But in ſuch Caſes where the King is Party, its Eſtabliſhed, <hi>that the Priſoners in all the King's Priſons, ſhould be maintain'd at the King's Charge, and out of the Kings Reve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nues, according to the Old Law of the Land:</hi> Much leſs to have Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney extorted from him by the Goaler. But look into the Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons in and about the City of <hi>London,</hi> what horrible Oppreſſions, Extortions and Cruelties, are exerciſed upon the Free-born Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of <hi>England,</hi> yea in moſt Priſons throughout this Kingdom?</p>
                  <p>So that by the Laws of the Land it appears, that thoſe who Sell, or take any manner of Reward for any publick Office or Place, or thoſe who do receive any greater Fee than therein is expreſt, have no more Property, Right or Intereſt to do it, than the Pirate has to the peaceable Merchant's Ship, a Robber to the inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cent Traveller's Purſe, or the Wolf to the blood of the harm<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs Lamb.</p>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>THUS we have traced our <hi>Diſtempers</hi> to their very Spring and Original. We have ſhown you the Danger of our pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Condition, the true cauſe from whence it aroſe, and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed an effectual Remedy againſt it for the future. It is the Magiſtrate's Duty now to accompliſh and perfect the Cure. I confeſs, a great deal of Reſolution is requiſite to make a thorough Reformation, and ſtop all thoſe bleeding Wounds, thro which the Government is inſenſibly breath<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:57429:20"/>out its very Life. Yet we are willing to aſſume more than an ordinary Confidence of the good ſucceſs of this Undertaking, conſidering that our great <hi>Senate,</hi> to their im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mortal Glory, in their laſt <hi>Addreſs</hi> to His <hi>Majeſty,</hi> have ſo eminently ſignalized their vigorous Zeal, and unſhaken Reſolution, of Reducing not only our own, but the Grand Enemy of <hi>Earope,</hi> to Reaſon. I am perſwaded that no one Thing can contribute more to the Accompliſhment of ſo Glorious a Deſign, than a timely and general Redreſs of the <hi>Greivances</hi> here Expoſed and Complain'd of. How chearfully wou'd the People of <hi>England</hi> receive the News of the <hi>Parliaments</hi> going about a work of this Nature, in relieving them from an Oppreſſion, under the weight of which, every <hi>Individual,</hi> at one time or other, has more or leſs Suffer'd? this wou'd not only enlarge their <hi>Hearts,</hi> but make their <hi>Purſes</hi> too more free and open, in furniſhing the Neceſſary Supplies which His <hi>Majeſties</hi> Affairs at this time ſo earneſtly require.</p>
            <p>It muſt indeed be acknowledged, That (thro' the Neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligence or Remiſneſs of the Magiſtrates) an evil <hi>Cuſtom</hi> may ſometimes obtain, and fix it ſelf ſo firm in the Intereſt or Opinion of the People, that there ſhall be leſs danger in Conniving at it, than in Endeavoring to Suppreſs it. But then it muſt not be ſuch as directly and deſignedly aims at the very Being of Government it ſelf, as This do's which we now ſo juſtly Regret. In ſhort, the Redreſs of this fatal Calamity can offend none, but ſuch contemptible Creatures whom 'tis more Honourable and Safe to Diſtaſte than Oblige; and ſure it can reflect no Blemiſh upon a Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment to ſay, <hi>They have taken away from</hi> Villains, <hi>the very Means and Temptation of being <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>njuſt and Diſhoneſt.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But as the Eaſing of Oppreſſion, and Unloading the Shoulders of the <hi>Poor,</hi> is the main Argument of this Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſe, ſo to puſh on the great Cauſe before us yet a little further; The <hi>Author</hi> hereof Declares, he is ready to De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monſtrate
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:57429:20"/>thoſe reaſonable Methods for Employing all the neceſſitous <hi>Poor,</hi> and likewiſe for encouraging many Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſands of <hi>Idle Perſons</hi> to ſet themſelves to Work, tho' they are not reduced to the Neceſſity of the former; which will be of ſuch public Service, and general Advantage, that even the Profits of their Labours and Induſtry, ſhall more than Advance the whole <hi>Taxes</hi> now raiſed; with ſeveral other uſeful Propoſals, abundantly conducing to the <hi>Benefit</hi> of Trade, <hi>Improvement</hi> of Navigation, <hi>Increaſe</hi> of Seamen, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Which, too long to be here ſet down, wou'd require a Treatiſe of it ſelf.</p>
            <p>Now to Conclude, I cannot but a little take Notice of the great Neglect of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> when thoſe Spiritual <hi>Pilots</hi> at the <hi>Helm</hi> of <hi>Religion,</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>, or at leaſt ought to <hi>Preach</hi> Univerſal Charity, and denounce the Commina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions and Judgments againſt all Oppreſſion and Injuſtice, have not <hi>publicly</hi> bore their Teſtimony againſt this Crying Sin, in the particular <hi>Nation?</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> before mentioned. Nor does the Duty of this <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> inſtrance, lye leſs upon the Great <hi>Stateſmen</hi> of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> the <hi>Steerers</hi> at the Temporal <hi>Helm,</hi> but rather more, by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>, as the imme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diate Care and Welfare of the <hi>Nation</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> is their nearer and more particular Charge and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>.</p>
            <p>But if all we have here urged in ſo juſt a Cauſe, ſhall be utterly Neglected, we have one farther unhappy circum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance to add to theſe deplorable Calamities now <hi>Threat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning</hi> us, which is, That <hi>Oppreſſion</hi> and <hi>Extortion</hi> will receive an Encouragement even from theſe very <hi>Papers,</hi> when the Cry of Juſtice <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nhear'd</hi> and <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nredreſs'd,</hi> will but harden their Iniquity; whilſt their <hi>Impunity,</hi> like an <hi>Igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ramus</hi> to a Capital Indictment, will be look'd upon as their <hi>Juſtification.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And then what aſſurance can we poſſibly have of enjoy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing our Rights, Liberties, and Eſtates ſafe from the Inva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of Ravenous and Mercinary Extortioners, who make
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:57429:21"/>no ſcruple of turning <hi>Butchers</hi> to the Peoples Priviledges, and Conſpirators againſt their Rights and Properties? Or, What proſpect can we flatter our ſelves with, of bringing our <hi>National</hi> Endeavours to a ſucceſsful Concluſion, while Judgment is turned back, Juſtice ſtands afar off, our An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tient and Fundamental Laws of <hi>Mercy,</hi> as well as the expreſs Commands of GOD, are turn'd into a Shadow; and Thoſe who wou'd reclaim theſe Evils, (in order to avert the juſt Judgment and Indignation of GOD, ready to break out againſt us) only draw on Themſelves the Frowns and Diſpleaſure <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>aged Violence, as a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compence of their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Labour?</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:57429:21"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
